譯者:微博@Emtee
私人采購
樓上用小鑰匙
So, um, the little key is for the lock up top.
樓下用大鑰匙
And the one for below.
你不留宿?
You're not staying?
我可不想 有太多回憶了
No, I prefer not to. Too many memories.
你不介意吧
It's good for you?
當然不介意 我理解
Yeah, of course. I understand.
- 再見 - 好的
- See you later. - Okay.
劉易斯?
Lewis?
劉易斯 是你嗎
Lewis, is that you?
劉易斯
Lewis!
茉琳
Maureen?
我不知道我睡著了
I don't know...  I fell asleep.
怎麽說
So?
有個存在體
There was a presence.
我感覺到了什麽 我只是...
I felt something. I just can't...
講不清 它太遠了
I can't tell, it was too far.
你必須建立聯繫
You must make contact.
我覺得這可能需要我們兩個才能做到
I think there might need to be two of us for that.
還不够吸引它
There... There wasn't enough pull.
因爲我感覺到了什麽 而它在保持距離
Because I felt something. It was just keeping its distance.
來
Come here.
看見十字印沒
You see the cross?
看見了
Yeah.
是一直在那的嗎
Has that always been there?
她說她沒法建立聯繫
She said that she couldn't make a contact.
她還是感覺有存在體嗎
Does she still feel a presence?
是啊 她說房子被占據了
Yes, she says the house is inhabited.
我們要確定了才能買
Well, we can't buy unless we're sure.
我們得知道它善不善良
We need to know if it's benevolent or not.
這投入太多了
It's too much of an investment.
嘿 那裏...
Hey... um... So, there...
可能什麽人都沒
Could be no one.
但可能有別的什麽 我需要更多時間
But there could be something. I-I just need more time, I think.
找到靈界入口是極爲困難的
It's extremely difficult to find a portal into the spiritual world.
這種事就是這樣
It's the way that it is.
我上周在斯德哥爾摩
I was in Stockholm last week,
我在現代藝術博物館看了一場精彩的展覽
I saw a wonderful exhibition at the Modern Art Museum.
希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特
Hilma af Klint.
你聽說過她嗎
Have you ever heard of her?
沒有
No.
她說 靈托她作畫
She says that spirits commission her paintings.
她在1906年 先于康定斯基和馬列維奇
She invented abstract art before Kandinsky and Malevitch
創造了抽象藝術
in 1906.
她宣稱
She claims that
靈界是通過她來與我們交流的
the spirit-world communicated with us through her.
希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特
抽象
先驅
發現希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特的作品時 讓我著迷的是
What fascinated me when I discovered Hilma af Klint's work was...
這些被畫于1900年代早期的
That these grand and enigmatic paintings
宏大的神秘之作
had been painted in the early 1900's.
它們出自一位我從未聽過的
And that they were made by a Swedish female artist
瑞典女藝術家之手
that I hadn't heard about before.
最讓人著迷的地方或許在于
Maybe the most fascinating part is that these pieces
這些作品被畫于抽象藝術概念出現之前
were made before the conception of abstract art.
但希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特對她的藝術做了保密處理
But Hilma af Klint kept her art secret,
她確信它們在她有生之年不會被理解
She was sure that they wouldn't be understood during her life.
她在遺囑中决定
In her will she decided that they would
等她逝世20年後 再將它們初展
be kept hidden until 20 years after her death.
百年前 希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特
So, a century ago, Hilma af Klint
給未來作畫
painted for the future.
而如今 未來已至
And the future is here now.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
在接待區不覺得太無聊嗎
It didn't bore you too much at reception?
不覺得 習慣了 我的護照丟了
No, no more than normal. I lost my passport.
- 她在米蘭待多久 - 兩天
- How long will she be in Milan for? - Two days.
我把所有東西都挂架子上了
I put everything on a rack.
有來自新成衣系列的皮褲
Here are the leather pants from the new collection.
這些是琪拉的風格 我看得出很適合她
They're Kyra's style. I mean, I can see her in them.
能剪裁嗎 有這可能嗎 太大了
Are we able to cut them? Is it possible? They'll be too big.
我拿去看看
Let me look into this.
我要去廠家幫你拿
I'll get them for you from the studio.
我真不該這麽做 但...
I'm not really supposed to, but...
請你儘快還回來
Please, you bring them back as soon as you can,
不然我會有麻煩
otherwise I will be in big trouble.
好的
Of course.
她需要更顯眼點的 出席美國艾滋病研究基金會晚宴
She's going to need something a little flashier for the Amfar dinner.
好的
Yeah.
這些是劉易斯挑出來用于晚宴的
That's the stuff Lewis set aside for the dinner.
劉易斯喜歡的話 她也會喜歡
If Lewis likes it, then she'll love it.
- 你喜歡這件?  - 嗯
- You like it? - Mm.
劉易斯也喜歡 這件很挑人
So does Lewis. It's not easy to wear.
性感而又剛毅
It's sensual and strong.
要這件了 還要靴子
I'll take it, and some boots.
好的
Okay.
那兩個包和這根皮帶 我要了
I think I'll take both bags and this belt.
你知道她的 我不想冒險
You know her. I don't wanna risk it.
琪拉肯定想要棕色的
Kyra would want the brown, for sure.
或者藍色的 或者都不要
Or the blue. Or neither.
她給了我張空白支票
Ah, she gave me a blank check.
- 你收押金嗎 - 收的
- Do... do you take deposits? - Yes.
- 4500 - 好的
- 4,500. - Cool.
皮帶500 包2000一個
500 for the belt, and 2,000 for each bag.
好的
Great.
茉琳 我回來過了 但我得趕時間
Maureen, I got back but I have to leave right away.
我們見不著面了 我明早去米蘭
We'll miss each other. I'm off to Milan tomorrow morning.
我留了個信封 裏面有過去兩周欠你的錢
I'm leaving an envelope with what I owe you for the last two weeks.
保重 琪拉留
Take care. Kyra.
附 我把蘋果電腦留桌上了
PS: I left my Mac on the desk.
你能幫我升級嗎
Can you do the upgrade for me?
蓋瑞來電
希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特進入了唯靈論者的圈子
Hilma af Klint has moved in spiritual circles
幷參與了降神會
and participated in seances,
後來她也成了靈媒
later she was also a medium.
唯靈論的本質到底是什麽
What actually is regarded as the essence of spiritualism?
唯靈論的中心思想是
Well, the central idea of spiritualism,
我們世界之外有著另一個世界
is the idea that there is a world beyond our world.
唯靈論者試圖給這個世界提供實踐證據
And spiritualists try to give empirical proof for this world.
1848年
In 1848,
福克斯姐妹聽到了敲擊聲
the Fox sisters heard rappings
她們把這些敲擊聲詮釋爲 是已故之人傳達的信息
and they interpreted these rappings as messages from deceased persons.
對她們來說 這是真正意義上的證據
And that was for them real proof
證明了我們的世界之外有著更高級的世界存在
for the existence of a higher world beyond our world.
有趣的是 莫爾斯電碼的發明比這早兩年
It's interesting that the Moriset code had been invented 2 years earlier.
唯靈論者總是很瞭解先進科技
The spiritualists were always very close to the technological avant-garde.
比如 第一張抽象照片
For example, the first abstract photographs
是由唯靈論者們拍的
have been taken by spiritualists.
希爾瑪·阿夫·克林特相信 她的抽象畫作
Hilma af Klint believed that she received the abstract paintings
領受于更高級的意識
from higher levels of consciousness.
當她開始作爲靈媒作畫時
When she started to paint as a medium,
她摒弃了她在美術學院學得的畫技
she rejected the skills she had learned at the art academy.
這是由于唯靈論和神智學的影響
And that was due to the influence of spiritualism and theosophy.
你提到了神智學
Now you mentioned theosophy,
魯道夫·施泰納是怎麽看待抽象藝術的
What was Rudolf Steiner's view on abstract art?
施泰納排斥抽象畫作
Steiner rejected abstract paintings.
但實際情况更複雜 有很多...
But that's not the whole story.A lot of...
嘿
Hey.
我一個禮拜都在聯繫你
I've been trying to reach you for a week.
我知道 我一直在工作
I know. I've been working.
很忙
A lot.
抱歉
Sorry.
和琪拉怎麽樣
How's it going with Kyra?
就沒見到過她
Ah... I never see her.
我們互相留言
We leave each other messages.
我其實討厭這份工作
I hate this job, actually.
我真他媽討厭她 她是個...
I fucking hate her. She's a...
你以前不是這麽說的
That's not what you said before.
以前待在巴黎 付付房租 就很開心
Yeah I was just happy to stay in Paris and pay my rent.
哪變了呢
Yeah, well, what's changed?
時間都用在一堆破事上
I spend my days doing bullshit.
我不喜歡 可又做不了感興趣的
That doesn't interest me, and it keeps me from what does.
我快他媽瘋了
It's driving me fucking crazy.
你應該來這裏
You should come here.
去阿曼蘇丹國?
Yeah, to the Sultanate of Oman?
我還要在這待兩個月
I'll be here another two months.
我還以爲你快完工了
I thought you were almost done?
我重配了大使館的電腦系統
I finished reconfiguring the embassy's computer system
現在在等安全協議
and now I'm just waiting for the security protocols.
你覺得你什麽時候能拿到
When do you think you'll get those?
可能明天 也可能下個月
It could be tomorrow, could be next month...
我一拿到 就開始安裝 配置
And once I get them I start the installing and configure them.
來馬斯喀特吧
Come to Muscat!
看 我來海邊過周末了
Look, I came to the seaside for the weekend.
很美
It's beautiful.
我去馬斯喀特做什麽呢
What the hell would I do in Muscat?
做你在巴黎做的事
What the hell you do in Paris?
你知道...
You know...
我在等 我得等著
I'm waiting. I have to wait.
已經三個月了
It's been three months.
我覺得我感覺到了什麽
I think I felt something.
我得回劉易斯家 我真覺得我感覺到了什麽
I need to go back to Lewis' house. I really think I felt something.
你覺得你感覺到了什麽 你確定嗎
You think you felt something or you're sure?
我得徹底搞清楚 就是這樣
I just need to see it to the end. That's all.
這件很完美 要這件 謝謝
This is perfect. This works. Thank you.
還有這件
This too.
我看看這件
I see this...
這件其實會很完美
Actually it may be perfect.
我想你穿上看看
I'd like to see them on you.
你不想穿上試試嗎
You don't want to try them on?
你瞭解她的 我不能穿
I... you know her. I can't.
但你想穿
But you want to.
沒錯 要是你不說出去 我或許會穿
Sure, I mean.. if you could keep your mouth shut, maybe...
但我上次穿了 你就出賣了我
but you totally dicked me over the last time I did it.
至少試下鞋子吧 我去拿
Try on the shoes at least. I'll get them.
和你的尺碼一樣 她不會把它們送回來的
They're the same size. She won't have to send them back.
好吧 維森特
Okay, Vincent...
你必須向我保證
You have to promise me...
一個字都不能說
Not one word. Not one word.
我的嘴已經封住了
My lips are sealed.
真的?
Really?
有車必有堵 你也沒辦法
If there's traffic, there's traffic. Nothing you can do about it.
他們會等
They'll wait.
他們正好需要點日光 沒事
They just need a little daylight. It's okay.
不行 我等不了 我有事
No, I can't wait. I have an appointment.
下午在你家碰面吧
I'll meet you at your place later this afternoon?
好的
Okay.
皮褲都很棒吧
The leather pants. They're great, right?
這些不行 你不能留著 我保證過...
No, not these..you can't keep... I promised...
我保證過要在早上帶回去
I promised that I'd bring them back in the morning.
請別這樣
Please don't do that to me.
我就去跟他們講 沒事的 別擔心 好的
I'm telling them right now. It's no problems. Don't worry. Okay.
嘿 她在路上 要晚到 從米蘭過來的飛機晚點了
Hey so, she is on her way. She's late. Her plane from Milan was just delayed.
但她在哪呢
But where is she?
她在高速公路上 顯然堵車了
She's on a highway. There's traffic, apparently.
你能代替她嗎 節省時間
Can you stand in for her? It'll save some time.
我四點必須走
I have to leave at four o'clock.
沒問題 太好了 來吧
Yeah, that's okay. It's perfect. Come.
你覺得她會全都改掉?
You think she'll ditch everything?
沒錯 她會全都改掉 不過我給了你三個選擇 你應該...
Yeah, she'll ditch everything. I brought you three options though.You should...
那樣就能通過了嗎
With that we'll make it through?
我保證不了
I can't make any promises.
你待著我會更自在
I'd feel more comfortable if you stayed.
你怕琪拉?
You scared of Kyra?
我聽說她是個怪物
I hear she's a monster.
這是你的左心室
This is your left ventricle.
只是稍微大了點
It's just slightly larger in size.
和你胞胎哥哥的完全一樣
It was exactly the same for your twin brother.
你不會有事 能活到100歲
You can live with it and die at 100.
或是27歲?
Or at 27?
我診療劉易斯和我診療你一樣
I treated Lewis just like I treated you.
每年兩次超聲波檢查
An ultrasound twice a year.
沒有過迹象 什麽都沒
There was no sign. Nothing.
有一天 它就停下了
One day, it just gave way.
別害怕 茉琳 劉易斯的事是特例
Don't be scared, Maureen. What happened to Lewis is very exceptional.
譯禇 嶶ъο Ｅмτèè
你能起身了
You can get up.
一切正常
Everything is fine.
你只需要避免劇烈的身體活動
You just need to keep avoiding both intense physical efforts
和過激情緒
and extreme emotions.
就像劉易斯那樣
Like Lewis did...
- 我意思是 他做了些櫃子  - 我知道
- I mean,... he built cabinets. - I know.
他想把房子弄成工作室
He wanted to turn the house into a studio
用來教授和練習木工
where he could teach and practice carpentry.
他真的認爲那是他的未來
He really considered it his future.
六個月後我們再見吧
I'll see you again in six months?
我不知道六個月後我會怎麽樣
I have no idea where I'm going to be in six months.
晚上好 茉琳
Good evening, Maureen.
不好意思 我們沒見過面
Excuse me, we haven't met.
我叫英戈
I'm Ingo.
你好 不好意思
Hi! Um, sorry...
琪拉在嗎
Is Kyra here?
和她的律師一起在她房裏
In her room with her lawyer.
在進行電話會議 已經一個小時了
They've been on a conference call for an hour.
和基金會有問題
Problems with the foundation.
我來拿幾樣東西 她知道的
I'm just here to pick up a few things. She's aware.
你知道在哪嗎
Do you know where they are?
那裏有個衣物袋
There is one garment bag over there.
隨口問下
Um, random question, but
你知道兩條皮褲在哪嗎
do you happen to know about two pairs of leather pants?
應該在袋裏的
They should be in the bag.
她想留著
She wants to keep them.
好吧
Okay.
她在那裏面?
She's just in there?
她真的很讓人討厭 對吧
Ah, she's a real fucking pain-in-the-ass, right?
我們爲此努力了六個月
We've been working on this for six months.
我們不能在最後一刻取消媒體采訪
We can't just call off the press trip at the last minute.
嘿 琪拉
Hey Kyra?
我們有頭兩歲的大猩猩 失踪三周了
We have a 2-year-old gorilla who's been gone for three weeks.
而現在這一家子都出問題了
And now we have a problem with the whole family.
蓋爾曼夫人的丈夫爲大猩猩栖息地的保護
Mrs. Gellman's husband invests a lot of time and money
投入了大量時間和金錢
into gorilla habitat preservation.
他非常關心大猩猩
He cares deeply about gorillas.
但如果出了岔子
But if things go wrong,
就會嚴重影響他的商業利益
this reflects really badly on his business interests...
嘿 琪拉 我能小問下嗎
Hey Kyra, can I just ask you one word quick question?
這很嚴重 你得處理好
This is serious. You need to take care of this.
在嗎
Hello?
母猩猩很抑鬱
The female is depressive.
公猩猩 納加博 你熟的 變得很有攻擊性
The male, Ngabo, you're familiar with him is becoming aggressive.
納加博在有壓力的情况下 會變得非常有攻擊性
Ngabo can become very aggressive in stressful situations.
我記得非常清楚 謝謝
I remember very well, thank you.
它們現在在哪 大猩猩們在哪
Where are they now? Where are the gorillas?
它們走得越來越深入山裏了
They wander off further and further into the mountain
很難監控它們
and it's difficult to monitor them.
我們不能取消記者采訪
We can't cancel the reporters!
我們有合同義務 我們需要看到那些大猩猩
We have contractual obligations. We need those gorillas to be there.
就小問下
Just one quick question?
我聽到的都是問題 而不是解决方案
I'm hearing problems, I'm not hearing solutions.
介意我抽烟嗎
Mind if I smoke?
你除了給琪拉配裝 沒別的事做了嗎
You have nothing better to do besides dress Kyra?
覺得很有意義嗎
Really find it worthy of your time?
你有更好的職務提供嗎
Do you have a better offer?
沒有
Not exactly.
我是時尚男士版的柏林通訊員
I'm a correspondent for Men's Vogue in Berlin.
我能幫你說說
I can put in a word for you.
謝謝
Thank you.
但雜志不適合我
But I..you know, magazines aren't really my thing.
都是狗屁
They sell shit.
主要面向廣告客戶 而不是讀者
Mainly for advertisers, rather than readers.
那又怎麽樣 你已經幹了份蠢工作
So what? You already have a stupid job.
這點上不會有任何變化
It wouldn't change a thing but,
然而薪水更多
it pays better.
不適合我
Not for me.
一些備受推崇的攝影師會在時尚雜志上刊登作品
Some highly-regarded photographers publish in fashion magazines.
免費?
Are they free?
我想是的
I suppose so.
是嗎
Yeah?
他們能選擇拍攝品牌和對象?
They get to choose their brands and subjects they shoot?
當然不能
No, that's correct.
我真不覺得這有自由可言
I don't really see the freedom in that.
好了 我要走了
Yeah, I'm going to go.
衣服和包我拿走了
I'll take the dress and the bags.
你得告訴她 她得還褲子
You really need to tell her she's gotta return those pants.
我明天再來
I'll come back tomorrow.
她明天在這嗎
Do you know she'll be here tomorrow?
你問她
Ask her.
她會叫我走人
She'll tell me to leave.
你不會走?
And you're not leaving?
我在等她開完會 我想跟她談話
I'm waiting for her to finish. I want to speak with her.
她想甩了我
She wants to dump me.
你們多久了
How long's it been?
兩年
Two years.
但她怕她丈夫發現
But she's scared her husband will find out.
我肯定他有所懷疑了
I'm sure he suspects something.
你愛上了她?
You in love with her?
愛?
Love?
沒有 我從沒有過這感覺
It never crossed my mind, no.
只是肉體上的
It's just physical.
你來巴黎做什麽
What are you doing in Paris?
我在等待
I'm... waiting.
我要走了
I'm gonna go.
你在等待什麽
What are you waiting for?
我哥哥死在這裏
My... uh... brother died here.
我的胞胎哥哥
My twin brother,
死在巴黎
died in Paris.
事故?
An accident?
不是
No.
心臟病
A heart attack.
實際上 我有相同的
I actually have the same...
先天畸形
malformation.
你怕嗎
Does it scare you?
不怕
No.
他也不怕
And it didn't scare him.
你待在這裏哀悼他
You stay here to mourn.
不是 我在等待
No, I'm waiting.
我跟你說了我在等待
I told you I was waiting.
你在等待什麽
What are you waiting for?
我們立過一個誓約
So, we made this oath.
不管誰先死  都要給另一個示以迹象
Whoever died first would send the other a sign.
迹象?
A sign?
從陰世?
From the afterlife?
你可以這麽稱呼 怎麽稱呼都行
You could call it that. You could call it a million things.
但你要怎麽知道是不是迹象
But how will you know if it's a sign?
我是個靈媒
I'm a medium.
他也曾是靈媒
He was a medium.
我就是會知道
I'll just know it.
你以前和靈交流過嗎
Have you communicated with spirits before?
劉易斯認爲有靈存在 我不太確定
Lewis thought there were... spirits. I'm less sure.
但...我交流過
But... y-yes.
某種程度上交流過
Somewhat.
我們身邊一直都
There are invisible presences...
有著看不見的存在體
around us, always.
無論是不是死人的魂 但...
Whether or not they're the souls of the dead, I don't know, but...
你成了靈媒 就會靈敏地感覺到某種...
When you're a medium, you just are attuned to a sort of...
氣場
vibe.
你說的氣場是什麽意思
What do you mean by vibe?
這是種直覺感知的東西 感覺就像...
It's an intuition thing. It's a feeling you...
你看到一扇門
You see this door...
它只開了一點點
It's only like slightly ajar.
我還認爲
I also think that...
魂
the soul...
在人死後會繼續存在
continues to exist after death.
我真不知道我信不信
I don't really know if I believe in that.
但劉易斯信
But Lewis did.
我必須給他的靈...
And I have to give his spirit...
隨你怎麽稱呼它
whatever you want to call it...
一個機會來證明他是對的
a chance to prove him right.
直到什麽時候
Until when?
我得到過一個迹象
I had a sign.
- 哦? - 沒錯
- Oh? - Yeah!
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
不確定 所以我仍在等待
No. That's why I'm still waiting.
然後?
And then?
然後我想我會過我的生活
Then I guess I'll live my life.
讓自己放下
Let it go.
我早上來找你
I'll come for you in the morning.
- 或更早些 有事就打我電話 - 好的
- Or before. Call when you want. - Okay.
嘿
Hey.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們考慮過了 我們要翻新
So we thought about it, and we're renovating.
我覺得這是劉易斯想做的
I think that's what Lewis would have wanted.
我只希望茉琳在這地方 有了劉易斯的靈陪伴
I just wanted Maureen to be at peace with this place.
能變得安寧
And with Lewis' spirit.
我只是想說
I... I just wanted to say one last...
劉易斯會很高興這房子又是你們的了
Lewis would have been very happy that this house is yours again...
我也很高興
And I'm very glad too.
現在這是你們的房子
Now, it's your house and...
我會把它忘掉
I'll forget it.
來吧
Come on.
我需要你給我更多
I need more from you.
我會需要你給我更多
I'm gonna need more from you.
再給我一個迹象
Give me one more sign.
什麽都行
Anything.
給我最微小的迹象
Give me the tiniest thing.
就這樣嗎
Is that it? Is that it?
最微小的迹象就好
Just the tiniest little thing...
你能看到我 但沒法跟我說話 是嗎
Is it that you can see me, you cannot talk to me?
劉易斯 我他媽不要你對水管做什麽
Lewis,I don't care what you do with the fucking plumbing.
我要你跟我說話
I need you to fucking talk to me!
求你了 我不明白
Please, I don't understand.
你不是我哥哥
You're not my brother.
未知號碼 我認識你
你也認識我
你要去倫敦
你是誰
猜猜看
不猜 回答我的問題
你是男是女
這有什麽關係嗎
你是真實的嗎
你是活人還是死人
是活人還是死人
劉易斯?
飛行模式
開啓
飛行模式 關閉
我想要你
別發了
我想要你 我會得到你
你怎麽弄到這個號碼的
我要屏蔽你了
你不再想知道我是誰了?
我在這裏 我看著你
我開玩笑的 我不在那
但我可能在倫敦
你想知道我在哪?
在哪
謝謝回復
我不會在倫敦
你放心了?
還是失望了?
你想要什麽
你
不是肉體上的
想先
建立聯繫
琪拉要的我都準備好了
I've prepared everything Kyra asked for.
兩件她從照片裏選的禮服
Two dresses she picked from the photograph,
還一件被拍得不是很好 但我覺得她會喜歡
and a third one that didn't photograph so well but I think she'll like it.
哪一件
Which one?
這一件
This one there.
是絲質透明硬紗
It's silk organza.
在照片裏會失去些光澤 但是
In a photo you lose some of the sheen but,
有光就真的很好看
It really plays well with the light.
沒錯 很棒
Oh yeah, it's cool.
真的很棒
It's really cool.
背帶也有不同的顔色譯禇 覹愽 Emtёё
The harness comes in different colours as well.
- 我可以看看嗎 - 可以
- Can I see them? - Yeah.
給 有金色 黑色 和裸色
There you go. We've got gold, black and nude.
要黑色
In black.
不是所有人都會喜歡 但我覺得琪拉穿上會很好看
Not for all tastes, but I think it'll look amazing with Kyra.
你想試試嗎
Do you want to try it?
來吧
Come.
我提議玩個游戲
我討厭游戲
不好意思
Sorry.
你想試試禮服嗎
You want to try the dress?
不了 我要兩種顔色 讓她可以選擇
No, I'll take it in two colours so that she has the option.
好的 我會都包裝好給你
Cool. I'll get it all packed up for you.
那就不玩游戲 搞別的
什麽意思
你在等火車嗎
沒錯
回答我的問題
你想成爲別人嗎
想
誰
我不知道
我沒法幫你知道
告訴我讓你感到不安的東西
恐怖片
爲什麽
有殺手 女人要逃命 要躲藏
讓你感到不安的是恐懼
你經常感到害怕嗎
不會
未知號碼
我在火車上 稍等
I'm on the train.Give me one second.
今晚我會把東西帶過去
I'll drop the stuff off this evening.
你什麽時候回去
When do you get back?
就算是下午早些時候 那...
Even if it's early afternoon,it's...
那也沒關係 我會幫你放在衣物袋裏
It's okay. It'll be ready for you in a garment bag.τгаηslаτed ьγ ωeiьо-Eмτee
我得從卡地亞拿首飾
I have to pick up the jewellery from Cartier,
但他們說都準備好了
but everything, they said, is ready.
可以的話 我更想要歐元
I would prefer it in euros if that's not a problem...
你從戴高樂機場回去的路上 能叫司機開到自動取款機那
You know you could ask your driver to stop at an ATM on the way back from CDG.
兩秒就好
It'll take two seconds.
It was 400.
沒錯 談的是400
Yeah.We agreed on 400.
還有幾張出租車票據
There are a couple of taxi receipts as well.
明天見
See you tomorrow.
昨天我試穿了雇我工作的那女人的鞋子
你爲什麽告訴我
因爲她不會讓我試穿
所以答案是禁忌的事?
百無禁忌就無欲無求
還有什麽是禁忌的
回答我的問題?
是的
你回來了嗎
回來了
你家?
琪拉家?
你怎麽知道
你想試試琪拉的禮服?
是的
因爲是禁忌的?
琪拉·蓋爾曼 美國艾滋病研究基金會 米蘭時裝周
譯{}者{}:{}微{}博{}@{}E{}m{}t{}e{}e
我穿了
你害怕了
是的
我以爲你想成爲別人
茉琳
聖拉扎爾康科德酒店 下午4點 724號房
你怎麽樣
How are you?
你確定那個靈不在那了?
You're sure the spirit isn't there anymore?
是的
Yes.
她吐出了靈質
She vomited this ectoplasm
然後離開了
and left.
靈質存留了一分鐘
And the ectoplasm lingered for a minute,
或更短 然後也消失了
or less and then also disappeared.
你知道她想要什麽嗎
Do you have an idea of what she wanted?
她很憤怒 很暴力
She was really angry. Very violent.
或許她想算帳
Maybe she had a score to settle.
我覺得她迷失了
I think she was lost.
我覺得她幷不想回來 我覺得她不會再去那
I don't think she wants to come back. I don't think she'll be there again.
劉易斯呢
And what about Lewis?
已經95天了
It's been 95 days.
杰羅姆和卡桑德拉買下了房子
Jérôme and Cassandre are getting the bigger house.
很好
Good.
劉易斯真的很喜歡他們 所以...
You know, Lewis really loved them so that's...
太好了
perfect.
你呢
What about you?
打算怎麽用那些錢
What'll you do with the money?
不用
Nothing.
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道我能買什麽
I'm not sure I can buy something else.
我對未來沒有足够的信心
I'm not confident enough about the future.
我懂
I feel you.
我不覺得你理解
I don't think you understand.
我絕對理解 相信我
I definitely understand. Trust me.
我遇到了一個人
I met someone.
你遇到了一個... 就像...
You met some...like you...
聽著
Look,
你肯定早就認識他了
You must've known him before.
算是吧
Well, kind of...
一個朋友的朋友
A friend of a friend.
劉易斯死後 他來聯繫我
After Lewis died, he reached out to me,
我們發展得很親近
and we grew closer.
你很驚訝
You're shocked.
沒有 這很好 我沒...
No. Good. I wasn't...
這是我沒想到的 不過 當然了
I wasn't expecting it but like, of course.
我會永遠愛劉易斯
I'll always love Lewis,
但我不能在哀悼中度過一生
but I can't spend my life in mourning.
我不喜歡哀悼
I'm not interested in mourning,
我已經承受過够多的痛苦了
Like suffering in pain, I've had enough.
我覺得我現在想好好過日子
I think now I want life.
有一天 你說過
The other day, you said
維克多·雨果 你說他和靈交流過
Victor Hugo actu... you know, you said that he communicated with spirits...
什麽意思 是真的跟它們說話?
What did you mean by that? Like actually talked to them?
是的
Yeah.
他流亡澤西島時  扭轉了處境
When he was exiled in Jersey, he turned tables.
他與著名的歷史人物交談
Like he conversed with famous historical figures like,
甚至包括聖經人物
even biblical ones.
那裏很漂亮
It's pretty out there.
怎麽交談的
How?
我真不知道
I don't really know.
我意思是口頭說還是用字母
I mean literally. Like verbally or with an alphabet?
不是用字母 他們試過 但靈拒絕了
No, no, not the alphabet. They tried, but the spirit refused.
那他怎麽做的
So what did he do?
用柱脚桌
With a pedestal table.
柱脚會敲擊地板 一次表示肯定  兩次表示否定
The leg would tap on the floor like, once for "yes", twice for "no".
或者一次表示A 兩次表示B 以此類推
Like one for "A", two for "B" and so on like,
26次表示Z
26 for "Z".
這要花的時間 多得驚人
That would take an unbelievable amount of time.
是的 手錄稿不計其數
Yeah. There were pages and pages of transcriptions.
一定都是瞎扯的
Well, that's gotta be bullshit.
- 那是編造的 - 不是
- That's invented. - Ah, no, no, no.
- 這絕不可能 - 沒有 他是真的相信
- There's no way that happened. - No he really believed it.
又不是用于出版 爲什麽要編造
It was not intended for publication. So, why invent it?
我認爲不管是誰手錄
I think whoever did the transcripts
肯定都會詳略結合 填補期間空檔
must have adapted them, filled in the gaps.
所以有點像速記?
So, like stenography? Kind of.
沒錯 類比得不錯
Yeah, that's a good analogy.
不過你感興趣的話
But if you're interested,
有部60年代的電視電影描述了那裏的降神會
there's a TV movie from the sixties that depicts the seance.
片子很糟 但似乎是準確再現
It's really tacky, but seems accurate.
我能幫你找下片名 不過你在Youtube上
I'll find the title for you, but if you type in like:
輸入 雨果+澤西島+靈動桌 就能找到了
"Hugo+Jersey+Turning Tables" on YouTube, you will find it.
你是瘋狗嗎
Crazy dog, aren't you?
在澤西島的維克多·雨果
一個被稱爲白衣女士的生物在第一天問了我一件我做過的事
The being called the white lady asked me on the first day a thing that I did.
我知道這樣的生物 不敢來 會跑開
I know that a being, afraid of coming, ran away.
有誰在這裏嗎
Is there someone here?
敲一下表示肯定
If yes knock once...
敲兩下表示否定
If no knock twice.
在我問你是誰之前 我先問你個問題
Before I ask you who you are, I'll ask you a question.
但你能從我的腦海中得知這個問題嗎
But first, this question, do you see it in my thoughts?
你想回答嗎
Do you want to answer it?
那說吧
Then talk.
山是我的墳墓
The mountain is my grave.
我是神的吐息 我上天下地 我想要天空 而大地想要我
I'm God's breath, I go up and down, I want the sky and the Earth wants me.
群星拉著我的頭髮 棺材釘固定著我的脚
The stars pull me by my hair and the nails of the coffin hold me by my feet.
黑暗朝我大喊 下來 太陽對我說 上來
The darkness screams to me: "Down!" And the Sun says "Up!" to me.
我是不安的地平綫
I'm the uncomforted of the horizon.
我是無數墳墓的守夜人
I'm the night watcher of countless graves,
清理空顱骨中的眼睛
emptying his eyes in empty skulls.
我是噩夢之源
I'm the cause of bad dreams.
聖拉扎爾康科德酒店 下午4點 724號房
發我張照片
我喜歡這樣的你
我覺得可笑 那不是我
我爲自己感到羞耻
我不知道我爲什麽過來
拿好鑰匙 你還會來的
- 打擾一下  - 什麽事
- Excuse me. - Yes?
我想知道724房是在誰的名下定的
I need to know what name was room 724 was booked under?
好的 稍等
Okay, just a second.
724...
是...
It was...
查到的是茉琳· 卡特萊特
Maureen Cartwright, I have.
不會的 我就是茉琳· 卡特萊特 誰付的房費
No, I'm Maureen Cartwright. Who paid for the room?
稍等
Just a sec.
抱歉 沒有信用卡信息
I'm sorry, there is no credit card information.
是提前用現金支付的
Was paid in advance in cash.
你還記得是男是女嗎
Do you remember if it was a man or a woman?
不知道 那時不是我當班
I don't know. I was not working at that moment.
你能問問你的同事嗎 你知道...
Would you ask a colleague? Do you know...?
這是家大酒店
It's a big hotel.
我不確定我幫得了你
I'm not sure I can help you with that.
謝謝
Thank you.
這些是你選的五件東西
These are the five pieces of your selection.
特別是巴黎新浪潮系列的藝術橋
And particularly the "Pont des Arts" of the "Paris Nouvelle" collection.
由18克拉玫瑰金和細石製成
Made of 18 carat rose gold and fine stones.
很好 很完美
C'est bien. Yes, it's perfect.
項煉 手鏈 戒指 還有手錶
The necklace, the bracelet, the ring and the watch,
但不包括這個 我從沒見過它
but excluding this. I've never seen that.
好的 我來著重介紹這四件東西
Okay. Let me focus on these four.
- 好的 - 我會幫你都準備好
- Okay. - I'll prepare everything for you then.
謝謝
Merci.
不客氣
You're welcome.
這個是全新的 首次發布
And this one is brand new, first time released.
所以沒人有
So nobody has it.
很好 這點很重要 謝謝
Oh, good. That's important. Thank you.
嘿 琪拉 你回來了?
Hey Kyra, you back?
抱歉 我進來了 我就放下袋子 好嗎
Sorry, I let myself in. I'm just gonna drop these bags for you, okay?
天呐
Jesus.
嗨嘿 琪拉 你還好嗎
Hey Kyra, you doing alright?
嘿
Hey?
準備好了嗎
Are you ready?
我開車開了...
I drove for...
大概兩分鐘 才意識到我在做什麽
2 minutes maybe before I realized what I was doing,
然後我就回去報警了
And I came back and called.
你爲什麽不早點報警
Why didn't you do it earlier?
我嚇壞了
I-I-I... I freaked out.
我逃跑了
I-I-I ran away.
你逃避一個存在體?
You ran away from a presence?
公寓後方...
There was a light on in the...
有燈亮著 我聽到了些聲音
back of the apartment, I heard something.
你在蓋爾曼夫人家做什麽
What were you doing at Mrs. Gellman's?
放幾個袋子
Dropping off a couple of bags.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我是個私人采購員
I'm a personal shopper.
她備受關注 沒空做...
She was very high profile and couldn't...
平常的事
do normal things, didn't have time.
我算是在這方面爲她做事
And I sort of assisted her in that.
你昨晚用了蓋爾曼夫人的電腦
You used Mrs. Gellman's computer last night.
或許吧
Um, maybe.
今天早上又用了
And again this morning.
你登陸了Gmail查看你的郵件
You check your messages on Gmail.
我們有記錄
We have the record.
那你幹嘛問
So, why are you asking?
你在她家睡過嗎
Did you sleep at her place?
睡過 我在她家睡過
Yes, I did. I slept at her place.
爲什麽
Why?
我不知道
Um, I don't know.
說實話 我從不那麽做
To be honest, I never do that.
你爲什麽不想說
Why did you hide it?
傻了
A stupid reaction.
或許 或許我...
Maybe, maybe I was...
覺得有點羞耻
a little ashamed.
你知道她今天要回家嗎
You knew she was coming home today?
知道 她從米蘭回來
Yeah. She was coming back from Milan,
要去馬拉喀什
and on her way to Marrakech.
我是帶飾品給她
I was dropping off some accessories for her.
什麽飾品
What accessories?
首飾
Jewellery.
什麽首飾
What jewellery?
很貴的卡地亞首飾
Very expensive jewellery from Cartier.
你放那了嗎
And you left it there?
放了 四個盒子 在兩個袋子裏
Yeah. In four cases in two bags.
你回去後它們還在嗎
Were they still there when you went back?
我不知道 我沒...
I-I-I don't know. I wasn't...
當時我沒顧及首飾
I wasn't considering the jewellery at that point...
我沒注意
I didn't notice.
我發你的消息 你告訴警察了嗎
回答我
如果吵醒了你 那我很抱歉
Sorry, if I woke you up.
我剛在對一個...
I was just stress-testing...
新的安全協議進行壓力測試
one of the new security protocols.
真他媽難配置
Really fucking hard to configure.
要花我一個月的時間
So, it's gonna take me a month.
最好的情况是這樣
Best case.
我要來見你
I'm gonna come see you.
你放弃了嗎
You giving up?
是的 不會出現
Yeah, it's not going to happen.
茉琳 這不是不會出現的問題
Maureen, it's not that it isn't going to happen,
而是根本不存在
it's that it doesn't exist.
人死後
After death,
什麽都不會留下
there's nothing.
我知道
I- I know.
這沒什麽的
And it's not that big a deal.
你跟我說過你心存希望
You told me that you had a hope...
你很希望...
Like you really hoped that...
當然了
Of course I do.
但不行
But, no.
我不相信
I don't believe.
我再也不想待在這了
I don't want to be here anymore.
我再也不想待在巴黎了
I don't want to be in Paris anymore.
我想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you too.
我要去山上幾天
I'm actually heading up the mountains for a few days.
你想去就快來 然後去那跟我碰面
If you want to, you can come quickly and meet me there.
也許…
Maybe...
這得看警察怎麽說
It really depends on what the police say.
得看旅行禁令有沒被解除
If the travel ban's been lifted or not.
警察?
The police?
是的 琪拉被謀殺了 你沒聽說嗎
Yeah, Kyra was murdered, you didn't hear that?
- 到處都報道了 - 什麽
- It's everywhere. - What?
新聞上都是
All over the news.
- 是我發現她的 - 被謀殺?
- I found her. - Murdered?
是誰殺了她
Who murdered her?
我不知道
I don't know.
真的太可怕了
It was really horr... It was, ah...
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
我不想說這個  太他媽可怕了
I can't talk about it. It was fucking horrible.
你要我晚點打過來嗎
You want me to call you back later?
我會打給你的
I'll call you.
皇冠廣場酒店 329號房 馬上過去
我會再等一小時
我知道你在看我發的消息 快過去
我也會去
你的鑰匙我有備用的
我在出租車上
我在你家樓下
下來
就現在
我正在上來
我在你門外的樓梯口了
皇冠廣場酒店 329號房
- 你還好嗎 - 挺好
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 他們...我能喝嗎 - 當然
- They... Can I have some? - Yeah, sure.
他們逮捕了英戈 他...
They arrested Ingo, and he...
他坦白了一切
and he confessed to everything.
他們解除旅行禁令了嗎
Did they lift the travel ban?
解除了 結案了
Yeah. The case is closed.
但你要作證?
But you'll testify?
是的 大概吧
Yes, yeah, probably.
你想來我家嗎
Do you want to come to my place?
想 我感覺...
Yeah. I feel, um...
現在我一個人很害怕
I'm scared when I alone now.
你要去見蓋瑞 對嗎
You're going to see Gary, right?
是的
Yes, Yep.
你不久前就該去了
You should have gone a while ago.
我本該聽你的
I should have listened to you.
走吧 我開車來的
Let's go, I have my car.
- 早 - 早
- Morning. - Morning.
你是劉易斯的妹妹?
You're Lewis' sister?
是的
I am.
我們在布勒學院相處過
We were together at l'École Boulle.
現在我在哥白林工廠工作
Now I work at the Gobelin workshops.
實際上 我很快就要走了
Actually, I should get going soon.
你應該留下來
You should stay.
如果可以的話
If you can.
-  我叫茉琳  - 我叫艾爾文
- Maureen. - Erwin.
- 很高興認識你 - 很高興認識你
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
我理解你可能接受不了
I understand that you might feel uncomfortable.
爲什麽
Why?
因爲我很快地取代了
Because I've taken Lewis' place.
劉易斯的位置
So soon.
完全沒有
Not at all.
你誤會了
You're mistaken.
他活著時 勞拉和我之間完全沒什麽
While he was alive, there was nothing between Lara and me.
說真的 我沒那麽想過
It didn't cross my mind. Honestly.
你知道人們爲什麽說死人會守護活人嗎
You know how they say, the dead watch over the living?
這問題我想過很多
I've thought about that a lot.
不只是因爲劉易斯是個靈媒
Not just because Lewis was a medium.
我不知道那是什麽意思
I don't know what that means.
對我來說 他是個對別人有很强直覺力的人
For me, he was someone deeply intuitive of others.
他理解未被言說的事物
He understood things that went unspoken.
是的
He did.
也許是因爲他知道他要死了
Maybe because he knew he was going to die.
我意思是我覺得他看到了我看不到的東西
I mean I felt that he saw things which I didn't.
也許你也看到了
Maybe you do too.
他認爲你有同樣的天賦
He thought that you had the same gifts.
我不知道
I don't know.
我...
I, ah..
曾想追隨他
Had a tendency to follow him.
他做事會想得很遠
He took things quite far.
至少對我來說很遠
Too far for me, at least.
我跟不上
I couldn't keep up.
我想說的是 有劉易斯在
All I mean is that with Lewis,
就好像沒有什麽是不可能的
nothing seems impossible.
許多宗教相信 魂徘徊一段時間後
Many religions believe that the soul wanders around for a while
才離開這個世界
before leaving this world.
他跟你談過這個?
Did he speak to you about that?
他對此很確信
He was convinced of it.
幾年前 媽媽死了
Years ago, Mum died,
他確信...
he was sure that...
她來看他了 是來跟他道別的
he was visited by her. That she came to say goodbye to him.
那像一場夢 但幷不是 那非常真實
That it felt like a dream, but not, that it was very real.
他能聞到她的味道 他能很清楚地看到她
He could smell her, he could see her so clearly... you know?
你信嗎
Do you believe that?
我信
Yeah, I do.
這和宗教無關 但我...
It's not a religion thing, but I...
我信
I do.
你認爲劉易斯在這裏嗎
Do you think Lewis is here?
我不這麽認爲
I don't think so.
我感覺到了他的存在
I feel his presence.
他在這裏
He's here.
這可能是你的愧疚之言
That might be your guilt talking.
你不必覺得愧疚
You don't need to feel guilty.
勞拉理應幸福
Lara deserves to be happy.
你也是
And you do too.
我想這麽想 但...
I like to think so but...
有什麽在阻止我
something is stopping me.
但願跟我沒關係
I hope it has nothing to do with me.
是沒關係
No.
但你也得讓自己從劉易斯的事中解脫出來
But you also have to free yourself of Lewis.
我希望他會讓我解脫
Well, I wish he'd let me.
無論他在哪
Wherever he is,
他都不會禁止你那麽做
he would never forbid it.
即使他不在了
And even if he's nowhere,
那也別忘了他的自由
hold onto the memory of his freedom.
付諸實際行動吧
Put it into practice.
我明白你的意思
I know what you mean.
我得走了
You know, I have to get going.
你會住幾天嗎
Will you be staying a few days?
就今晚 我明天走
Just tonight. I leave tomorrow.
- 那今晚再見  - 好的
- So, I'll see you tonight. - Okay.
待在外面
Stay outside.
真乖
Good dog.
怎麽了
What happened?
玻璃杯碎了
A glass broke.
我以爲你在外面
I thought you were outside.
艾爾文剛走
Erwin just left.
他肯定把它放在桌子邊緣了
He must have left it on the edge of the table, or something.
但願你一路上都挺好
I hope you had a good trip.
先休息下吧
Get some rest.
你的司機叫瑟林
Your driver is named Salim.
最好在天亮前出發
It's best to leave a little before daybreak.
有五個小時的車程
Count on a five hour ride.
別擔心 一路上很安全 即便不是人來車往
Don't worry, the road is safe, even if it is not very busy.
東西能不帶就別帶 需要的我都有
Take the minimum. I have everything we need.
也就是說 東西不是很多
In other words, not much.
你沒問題的話 我們就待上一周
If it's okay with you, we'll stay for a week.
這是斯巴達式的生活 你必須忍受
You'll have to be tolerant, it's spartan.
不過你跟我說過 這是你想要的
But you told me this is what you wanted.
米斯法老房子旅館
哈吉?
Hajji?
劉易斯?
Lewis?
你在這嗎
Are you here?
你一直在等我嗎
Have you been waiting for me?
你平靜嗎
Are you at peace?
謝謝
Thank you.
你不平靜嗎
Are you not at peace?
你在耍我嗎
Are you playing with me?
你有惡意嗎
Do you mean harm?
我不認識你
I don't know you.
你是誰
Who are you?
劉易斯 是你嗎
Lewis, is it you?
還是 只是我
Or is it just me?
譯者:微博@Emtee